<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-06-04T23:02:12+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Flatmountain</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/26/flatmountain.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Flatmountain" /><published>2025-05-26T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-05-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/05/26/flatmountain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/26/flatmountain.html"><![CDATA[<p>This specialty coffee roastery and café serves as an unexpectedly calm haven amidst the chaos of Woodstock Main Road.</p>

<!--tldr-->

<figure>
    <img src="/assets/images/2025-05-26-flatmountain/flatmountain.jpg" alt="Flat Mountain Coffee Ritualists" />
    <figcaption>Cute windows!</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Flat Mountain is one of my favourite spaces to go for a coffee and a light lunch. These guys really know what they are doing when it comes to coffee! The espresso is beautifully balanced, with a lot of flavour but not overly bitter or burnt. Their milk is always steamed to perfection, giving the coffee that lovely smooth and creamy texture.</p>

<p>They offer all sorts of drinks, hot and cold - I would highly recommend giving their cocoa coffee or strawberry matcha smoothies a try. In terms of food, both Keshet and Ntando struggled to find something to order. I thought their menu was just perfect, but I guess it’s not for everyone. Consider giving the menu a read to see if it suits your style.</p>

<p>Stylishly decorated with mid-century modern decor, Flat Mountain is a charming spot for a casual meeting or to spend a few hours doing some remote work. They have great taste in music, and have clearly put some thought into sound insulation as it is never too loud to chat despite it being a roastery on a busy street.</p>

<p id="these-images">
<img src="/assets/images/2025-05-26-flatmountain/flatmountain_drinks.jpg" width="45%" />
<img src="/assets/images/2025-05-26-flatmountain/flatmountain_retail.jpg" width="45%" />
</p>

<p><strong>Retail</strong>:
Their carefully roasted and ethically sourced coffee beans are available to buy at very good prices for the quality of the product, and these are the beans Keshet and I use 99% of the time at home. They have a wide range of beans suitable for various preferences and brewing methods, and are more than happy to offer information and advice about what would work best for you. We usually favour a single origin Ethiopian bean with a more fruity flavour profile for pourover, but we also keep in stock a darker roast (look for flavour notes like “dark chocolate” or “tobacco”) for our strong-espresso-loving friends.
They are the only place in the area to stock the Specialty Coffee Magazine, so I  at least once a quarter to pick up the latest copy.</p>

<p>I highly recommend Flat Mountain to any coffee connoisseurs, as well as anyone looking for a good space in the area to meet up with friends, have a casual meeting, or do some remote work.</p>]]></content><author><name>kid</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This specialty coffee roastery and café serves as an unexpectedly calm haven amidst the chaos of Woodstock Main Road.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2025-05-26-flatmountain/flatmountain.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2025-05-26-flatmountain/flatmountain.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Oumeul</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/26/oumeul.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oumeul" /><published>2025-05-26T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-05-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/05/26/oumeul</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/26/oumeul.html"><![CDATA[<p>This review has not yet been written</p>

<!--tldr-->]]></content><author><name>keshet</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This review has not yet been written]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2025-05-26-oumeul/oumeul.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2025-05-26-oumeul/oumeul.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bananas</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/28/bananas.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bananas" /><published>2025-02-28T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-02-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/02/28/bananas</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/28/bananas.html"><![CDATA[<p>I like bananas.</p>

<!--tldr-->

<p>banana bread,
banana smoothie,</p>

<p>banana make nice baked goods like baked oats.</p>

<p>banana fresh,
banana frozen,</p>

<p>artificial banana flavoured candy,</p>

<p>banana amazing.</p>

<p>we love banana.</p>

<p>Bananas are a great way to improve a space.</p>]]></content><author><name>kid</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I like bananas.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2025-02-28-bananas/bananas.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2025-02-28-bananas/bananas.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Grapefruits</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/28/grapefruits.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Grapefruits" /><published>2025-02-28T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-02-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/02/28/grapefruits</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/28/grapefruits.html"><![CDATA[<p>No fruit truly encapsulates the ups and downs of life like the grapefruit.</p>

<!--tldr-->

<p>Fun memories of the grapefruit include sitting on the stoep at my Oupa’s house in my home town of Swellendam. Getting through the grapefruit peel is a task unto itself; getting through it while maintaining the integrity of the segment is an even more significant task.</p>

<p>Each new grapefruit I consumed over my stay, I became more meticulous and effective at unwrapping the precious fruit inside. Once one has made their way through the challenging exterior to reveal the juicy gem, they are greeted with a bittersweet reward.</p>

<p>The grapefruit reflects the truth of life itself. Throughout the ceaseless toil of life, we are rewarded with sweet victory as well as bitter challenges. In learning to appreciate the bitter pith that encases the sweet sap, we can learn to live life to the fullest.</p>]]></content><author><name>keshet</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[No fruit truly encapsulates the ups and downs of life like the grapefruit.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2025-02-28-grapefruits/grapefruit.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2025-02-28-grapefruits/grapefruit.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>