<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-05-26T20:25:34+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Flatmountain</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/26/flatmountain.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Flatmountain" /><published>2025-05-26T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-05-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/05/26/flatmountain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/26/flatmountain.html"><![CDATA[<p>tl;dr: I highly recommend Flat Mountain to any coffee connoisseurs, as well as anyone looking for a good space in the area to meet up with friends, have a casual meeting, or do some remote work. However, if you’re looking for an opulent space and a big meal, this might not be the one for you.</p>

<!--tldr-->

<p>Flat Mountain Coffee Ritualists in Woodstock is one of my favourite spaces for a coffee and a light lunch. Their prices are very reasonable especially considering the quality, and they offer a lovely discount when you order food and a drink. The food is mostly “health food” style (think Kauai), and often contains bacon or is reliant on the meat aspect to be filling. As such, Keshet (pescatarian) and Ntando (prefers burgers over quinoa) were not 100% satisfied with the food options.</p>

<p>As a specialty coffee roastery and café, they have brilliant coffee even to the connoisseur and they offer specialty brews. Their smoothies are fantastic - try the cocoa coffee~ or the strawberry matcha smoothie. Even my mom ordered herself a second smoothie when we visited together, which is something I’d never seen her do! For the matcha lovers, their matcha is quite meek and might be more accurately described as a vanilla steamer with a hint of matcha. Regardless, I order it every time - it’s a tasty vanilla steamer!</p>

<p>Stylishly decorated with mid-century modern furniture, Flat Mountain serves as an unexpectedly calm haven amidst the chaos of Woodstock Main Road. The furniture achieves a careful balance of modern, practical and clean coffee tables and chairs, with some more rough-around-the-edges eclectic pieces that foster a unique atmosphere. Flat Mountain roasts their beans in the café, which naturally leads to some noise when they are busy roasting. This can add to the ambience, but for those who want more peace and quiet, there are some areas such as upstairs that are a little sheltered from the noise. The roaster is often not in active use, so this is not always a concern.</p>

<h3>Retail</h3>

<p>Their carefully roasted and ethically sourced coffee beans are available to buy at very good prices for the quality of the product, and these are the beans Keshet and I use 99% of the time at home. They have a range of beans suitable for various preferences and brewing methods, and are more than happy to offer information and advice about what would work best for you. They of course offer to grind the beans for you if you don’t have a coffee grinder at home. We have tried almost all of their varieties and have always been happy! We usually favour a single origin Ethiopian bean with a more fruity flavour profile for pourover, but we also keep in stock a darker roast (look for flavour notes like “dark chocolate” or “tobacco”) for our strong-espresso-loving friends.</p>

<p>I highly recommend Flat Mountain to any coffee connoisseurs, as well as anyone looking for a good space in the area to meet up with friends, have a casual meeting, or do some remote work. However, if you’re looking for an opulent space and a big meal, this might not be the one for you.</p>]]></content><author><name>kid</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[tl;dr: I highly recommend Flat Mountain to any coffee connoisseurs, as well as anyone looking for a good space in the area to meet up with friends, have a casual meeting, or do some remote work. However, if you’re looking for an opulent space and a big meal, this might not be the one for you.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bananas</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/28/bananas.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bananas" /><published>2025-02-28T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-02-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/02/28/bananas</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/28/bananas.html"><![CDATA[<p>I like bananas.</p>

<!--tldr-->

<p>banana bread,
banana smoothie,</p>

<p>banana make nice baked goods like baked oats.</p>

<p>banana fresh,
banana frozen,</p>

<p>artificial banana flavoured candy,</p>

<p>banana amazing.</p>

<p>we love banana.</p>

<p>Bananas are a great way to improve a space.</p>]]></content><author><name>kid</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I like bananas.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Grapefruits</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/28/grapefruits.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Grapefruits" /><published>2025-02-28T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-02-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/02/28/grapefruits</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/28/grapefruits.html"><![CDATA[<p>No fruit truly encapsulates the ups and downs of life like the grapefruit.</p>

<!--tldr-->

<p>Fun memories of the grapefruit include sitting on the stoep at my Oupa’s house in my home town of Swellendam. Getting through the grapefruit peel is a task unto itself; getting through it while maintaining the integrity of the segment is an even more significant task.</p>

<p>Each new grapefruit I consumed over my stay, I became more meticulous and effective at unwrapping the precious fruit inside. Once one has made their way through the challenging exterior to reveal the juicy gem, they are greeted with a bittersweet reward.</p>

<p>The grapefruit reflects the truth of life itself. Throughout the ceaseless toil of life, we are rewarded with sweet victory as well as bitter challenges. In learning to appreciate the bitter pith that encases the sweet sap, we can learn to live life to the fullest.</p>]]></content><author><name>keshet</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[No fruit truly encapsulates the ups and downs of life like the grapefruit.]]></summary></entry></feed>